Michael Curran

Developer

Passionate web developer using HTML5 and CSS and JS to build all aspects of web applications. I pride myself on understanding and delivering on client's expectations through excellent communication and rational problem-solving. My experience has taught me that even the most daunting tasks a developer can face can be overcome by thorough research, strategic planning, and a thoughtful approach.

Work Experience

React Developer at GreakTech

January 2021 - Current

Currently working on projects utilizing React and Next.js. Focusing on developing accessible and responsive Ul's. Responsibilities include,

- Identifying bugs and implementing fixes
- Creating and consuming REST API's and API calls
- Implementing enhancements that improve responsiveness

Back End Developer Intern at Mind Home

January 2021 - February 2021

Used Python to implement server-side logic and scripts for a SaaS platform that connects IoT devices to a central hub for smart homes.

 Increased scalability of smart home systems by implementing AWS elastic beanstalk deployments.

Developer at Freelance

March 2018 - Present

Currently advising and developing all aspects of client applications from web and graphic design to server-side back-end logic.

- Reduced bounce rates by up to 17% by simplifying UI/UX Design.
- Creating inspired and unique graphic designs and logos while adhering to the client's brand using Adobe Illustrator and Adobe Photoshop

Recent Personal Projects

TokenCheck created on Jamstack

This app interacts with the Cardano Blockchain to verify ownership of CNFTs and allow users to post them to Twitter as their profile picture. Uses a Supabase PostgreSQL instance and the UI created with Sass and ChakraUI. https://tokencheck.app

Contact Details

Phone: 386-690-0749

Email: Mcurran1722@gmail.com Location: Colorado Springs, CO Github: Github.com/micurran Portfolio: MiCurran.dev

Blog: micurran.hashnode.dev/

Expertise

Javascript	5 years
Node.js	3 years
MYSQL & MongoDB	3 years
Rest API's	3 years
React & Next.js	3 years
Sass	2 years
Amazon Web Services	1 year
Tailwind CSS	1 year

Certifications

CIW Site Development Associate

2019 - Present

Volunteer Work

Volunteer Developer Spicy Green Book 2020 - 2021

Education

B.S. - Computer Science
Western Governors University
2019 - Present

A.S. - Computer

Programming and AnalysisDaytona State College